My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was shrunken by a mysterious organization!
تعرّض جسم طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي للتقلّص بفعل منظمة غامضة
If they found out that Shinichi and Conan are the same person,
إن وجدوا أنّ شينتشي وكونان هما الشخص نفسه
everyone close to me would be in danger!
!سيقع جميع من حولي في خطر
I can't even tell Ran, my childhood friend,
لا يمكنني إخبار صديقة طفولتي ران
or her detective father, Kogoro!
!أو والدها المتحرّي، العمّ كوغورو، فأخفي هويّتي
There's only one truth again today!
!واليوم تبقى الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
The Antique Collector Murder.
جريمة قتل جامع الآثار
There's no doubt about it.
لا شكّ في الأمر
Your wife is cheating on you.
زوجتك تخونك
I knew it!
!كنتُ أعرف
Have a look at the mole under her eye.
انظر للشامة تحت عينها
This woman is none other than your wife, Maru Ineko-san!
تلك المرأة ليست سوى زوجتك نفسها، مارو إينيكو-سان
It jumped again!
!قفزت مجدداً
How long is Kogoro going to make us wait?
يا إلهي، إلى متى سيجعلنا العم كوغورو ننتظر؟
He said he was going to take us out to eat for once,
قال أنّه سيدعونا للأكل من باب التغيير
but then he had to stop by this place first...
لكن كان عليه المرور بهذا المكان أوّلاً
What detective in their right mind would bring a kid along
أيّ مُتحرٍّ في عقله سيصطحب صبياً
when informing someone about their spouse's affair?
عند إخبار عميل بعلاقة زوجته العاطفية؟
A visitor?
زائر؟
Who in blazes is this man?!
!من هذا الرجل؟
I don't know that yet...
...لا أعرف بعد
A visitor?
زائر؟
Hey! Get the door! Is anyone there?!
!ردّوا على الباب! ألا يوجد أحد؟
Oh, that's right...
...صحيح
I asked the housekeepers to waste time outside since you were coming.
طلبت من مُدبّرات المنزل إهدار بعض الوقت خارجاً بما أنّك كنت قادماً
Excuse me while I see my visitor to the cottage.
اعذرني بينما أصطحب ضيفي للكوخ
I will return soon!
سأعود سريعاً
Certainly.
خذ وقتك
Sorry to keep you waiting. Let's go to the cottage.
أعتذر على الإطالة، لنذهب للكوخ
That's annoying! What's that old man doing, anyway?!
!يا للإزعاج! ما الذي يفعله ذلك الرجل؟
He probably can't hear it because he's in the cottage!
لا يمكنه السماع لأنّه في الكوخ غالباً
What the hell?!
!تبّاً
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Did you hear anything strange just now?
ألم تسمعي صوتاً غريباً؟
No, not really...
كلا، لم أسمع شيئاً
Hey, isn't he taking kind of long?
ألم يتأخر ذاك الرجل؟
Yeah, he sure is...
معك حق
What could he be doing?
ما الذي يفعله يا ترى؟
Huh? They hung up?
ماذا؟ أغلق الخطّ؟
They hung up after one ring...
أغلقه بعد رنّة واحدة؟
Where in the world is he?! It's been two hours now!
!ما الذي يفعله ذاك الرجل؟ مضت ساعتان
Another single ring! What's going on?
رنّة واحدة مُجدداً، ما الذي يجري؟
I've had enough! I'm going to the cottage!
!اكتفيت! سأذهب للكوخ
Man, am I hungry...
...أشعر بالجوع
What the...?
ما الخطب؟
What is it?!
!ماذا هناك؟
Who are you people?!
!من أنتم؟
No, who are you?!
!بل من أنتما؟
We're the housekeepers here!
!نحن مدبّرتا هذا المنزل
What is all this ruckus?
لمَ هذه الجلبة؟
Madam!
!سيّدتي
Just what is happening here?
ما الذي يجري بالضبط؟
I found this man snooping around inside the house!
!وجدتُ هذا الرجل يتطفل في البيت
A thief?!
!لصّ؟
No! I'm a detective-- I was hired by this house's owner!
!كـ-كلا! أنا مُتحرٍّ عيّنه مالك هذا البيت
A detective?!
مُتحرٍّ؟
What business does a detective have here?!
وما لدى المتحرّي هنا؟
You should ask your husband directly...
...عليك سؤال زوجك شخصياً
Where is my husband?
أين زوجي؟
He went over to the cottage and hasn't come back...
ذهب للكوخ ولم يعد بعد
Go bring my husband here.
ناديا على زوجي
Yes, Madam!
حاضر
So how much did you find out?
إذاً، كم عرفت؟
I'll pay you twice as much as he is! Just keep my affair a secret!
!سأدفع لك ضعف ما سيعطيك !فقط ابق أمر علاقتي سرّاً
Um, Miss!
...لـ-لحظة، سيّدتي
What is it?!
!ما الخطب؟
My husband!
!عزيزي
Ran! Call the police!
!ران! اتّصلي بالشرطة
Right!
!حسناً
The victim is Maru Denjiro, 51 years old.
الضحيّة مارو دينجيرو، 51 عاماً
This house's owner...
...مالك هذا المنزل
Your husband practiced Iai swordsmanship, is that right?
كان زوجك سيّاف أسلوب إياي، أليس كذلك؟
Yes. He was a 3rd-degree master.
بلى، كان أستاذاً في الدرجة الثالثة
He must have been rather skilled, then...
لا بدّ أنّه كان بارعاً إذاً
Was this really his sword?
أكان هذا سيفه حقاً؟
From the condition of this room,
،نظراً لحالة هذه الغرفة
it appears he and the murderer had quite the swordfight.
يبدو أنّه خاض مبارزةً حادّة مع القاتل
Which means that the killer must have been an expert swordsman as well.
مما يعني أنّ القاتل كان سيّافاً بارعاً بدوره
Is this the victim's organizer?
أهذا دفتر تنظيم الضحية؟
It's filled with appointments...
إنّه مليء بالمواعيد
Conan-kun. You're certain you saw the visitor, right?
كونان-كن، أنت متيقن أنّك رأيت الزائر، صحيح؟
Yes. But just his legs.
أجل، لكن ساقيه فقط
Let's see here. Today, he was to meet...
...حسنٌ، كان يُفترض أن يلتقي اليوم
Mori Kogoro, Suwa Yuji, Hatano Ikuya, and Akutsu Makoto...
موري كوغورو وسوا يوجي وهاتانو إيكويا وأكوتسو ماكوتو
These four people.
هؤلاء الأربعة
Inspector! We found a suspicious man!
!سيّدي المفتش! وجدنا رجلاً مريباً
What?!
ماذا؟
This man was prowling about in front of the house!
!كان هذا الرجل يتلصص أمام المنزل
I'm not suspicious!
!لستُ مريباً
Oh! Dr. Hatano!
!هاتانو سينسي
Hatano? This Hatano Ikuya-san?
هاتانو؟ نفسه هاتانو إيكويا-سان؟
Yes! He's my husband's doctor!
أجل، إنّه طبيب زوجي
He gives him health checkups every week.
يجري فحوصاً أسبوعية عليه
His doctor, eh...
...طبيبه
Let go! Let go, I say!
!دعوني! دعوني! أخبرتكم أن تدعوني
Do you have any idea who I am?!
!أتعرفون من أكون؟
I'm Akutsu-sensei, the great engraver!
!أنا أكوتسو سينسي، النحّات العظيم
Akutsu? Akutsu Makoto?
أكوتسو؟ أكوتسو ماكوتو؟
So 3 of the 4 people from his organizer are here.
هكذا ظهر 3 من الأربعة في الدفتر
I've got it!
!وجدتُها
The killer would be the person who had already been here!
القاتل هو الرجل الذي أتى لرؤية الضحية سلفاً
And that person would be the last one to show up: Suwa Yuji-san!
!ولم يظهر بعد، إنه سوا يوجي
What's this about me, now?
ماذا عني؟
I am Suwa. What exactly is all the commotion here about?
أنا سوا، ما سبب كلّ هذه الجلبة؟
What's with this boy?
ما خطب هذا الصبيّ؟
You're getting in the way again?!
!أنت تشاغب مُجدداً؟
You're a swordsman, aren't you, mister?
أنت سيّاف يا عم، صحيح؟
How did you know that, my boy?
كيف عرفت يا فتى؟
Your left hand.
يدك اليسرى
My left hand?
يدي اليسرى؟
See that small scar between your thumb and index finger?
توجد ندبة صغيرة بين إبهامك وسبّابتك، صحيح؟
People who practice swordsmanship often cut themselves there
يصاب بها المتمرّنون على فنّ السيف عادةً عندما يعيدونه
when sheathing their swords!
إلى غمده
So that's why I figured you were into swords.
لذا ظننت أنّك سيّاف
Is he right?
أهو مُحق؟
Yes, though I acquired this scar when I was still inexperienced...
أجل، رغم أنّي أصبت بهذه الندبة عندما كنت لا أزال صغير الخبرة
So you really are the culprit, then!
!أنت المجرم إذاً
Culprit?! What are you talking about?
المجرم؟! ما الذي تقوله؟
H-How did this happen?!
!لـ-لمَ حصل هذا؟
Are you implying that I did this?!
!أتقصد أنّي من فعل هذا؟
It's obvious when you look at this place!
الأمر جليّ بالنظر لأرجاء المكان
The killer was clearly a skilled swordsman!
كان القاتل سيّافاً بارعاً
In other words, you!
!مما يعني أنّه أنت
You've got it all wrong!
!أ-أخطأت
I'm only here to pay back Maru-san the 5 million yen he lent me!
أتيتُ لإعادة الخمسة ملايين ينّ التي استعرتُها من مارو-سان فقط
You're here to pay off a debt?
أتيت لردّ دين؟
Here is the money, as you can see.
ها هو المال كما ترون
The murder took place between 3 and 5 o'clock.
وقعت الجريمة بين الساعة الثالثة والخامسة
Where were you during that time?
أين كنت حينذاك؟
I believe I was meditating alone at my dojo...
أظنني كنت أتأمل بمفردي في الدوجو
Is there anyone who can verify this?
أهناك من يشهد على ذلك؟
N-No.
كـ-كلا
Suspicious...
...مُريب
Hey, that's not right!
هناك أمرٌ غريب
Not right?
غريب؟
The way he's holding his sword... it's backwards!
إمساكه للسيف... إنّه مقلوب
She's right! Look at that picture!
!صحيح! انظروا لتلك الصورة
The corpse's hands are holding it the wrong way!
!يد الجثة تمسكه بالشكل الخطأ
So does that mean someone put the sword in his hands afterwards?!
مما يعني أنّ أحدهم وضع السيف بيده لاحقاً؟
Plus, regardless of how much they may have fought,
،كما أنّه مهما كان القتال حاداً
it's still unnatural for the walls and ceiling to be cut this badly!
من غير الطبيعي أن يتضرر السقف والحوائط لهذا الحد
Ah! So the killer tried to frame Suwa-san
هكذا إذاً، حاول القاتل إلفاق التهمة بسوا-سان
by cutting up everything in the room with a sword?
بتقطيع كلّ شيء في الغرفة بما أنّه كان سيّافاً؟
But the killer made a mistake
لكن أخطأ القاتل
by messing up the corpse's grip on the sword!
بوضعه المعكوس للسيف في قبضة الضحيّة
Akutsu-san! What about you?
أكوتسو-سان، ماذا عنك؟
I borrowed money from Maru-san too... 10 million yen...
استعرتُ مالاً من مارو-سان أيضاً، 10 ملايين ينّ
Did you come to pay him back?
وأتيت لإعادتها؟
No, I needed more time, so I came to ask for an extension...
كلا، احتجتُ وقتاً إضافياً لذا أتيت لطلب مهلة
Where were you between 3:00 and 5:00?
أين كنت بين الثالثة والخامسة؟
I was by myself at my studio.
كنتُ بمفردي في غرفتي
So you don't have an alibi, do you?
لا تملك حجّة غياب إذاً، صحيح؟
What did you come here for?
ما الذي جلبك أنت هنا؟
Who, me?
أ-أنا؟
Of course. The victim planned to see you today, too.
بالطبع، خطّط الضحية لرؤيتك أيضاً
You can't be serious!
!بربّك
I simply came to report about something he hired me to look in to.
أتيتُ لتقديم تقريري عمَّ كلفني به فقط
To see if his wife was cheating on him or not.
بشأن خيانة زوجته
She was cheating on her husband?!
!خيانة الزوجة؟
Jeez! Detectives aren't supposed to tell people about their cases!
يا إلهي، يُفترض ألا يبوح المتحرّيين بأسرار القضايا للغير
Where were you when the murder took place?
أين كنت عندما وقعت الجريمة؟
Let me think...
...حـ-حسناً
Huh? This man smells different...
ماذا؟ رائحة هذا الرجل غريبة
I saw a movie in Ginza at 3:00...
...رأيتُ فيلماً في غينزا عند الثالثة
It's a woman's perfume...
إنّه عطر امرأة
I often see movies there...
عادةً ما أشاهد الأفلام هناك
Wait, I just smelled this somewhere before...
لحظة، شممتُ هذه الرائحة قبل قليل
Stop that, Conan-kun!
كونان-كن
It's rude to sniff at people like that!
من الفظّ تنشّق الآخرين هكذا
I wasn't doing anything!
!لم أكن أفعل شيئاً
It's her smell!
!إنّها رائحتها
Does that mean...
..مما يعني
You smell just like the doctor does!
رائحتك كرائحة الطبيب يا عمّة
He's right. It's the same perfume.
معه حق، نفس العطر
Do you wear women's perfume?
أتضع عطر نساء؟
No...
...كلا، أنا
I know! Don't tell me you're the one she's been seeing on the side?!
!فهمت! أيمكن أنك الطرف الآخر في الخيانة؟
It's true!
!صحيح
I'll confess now that there's no point in hiding it,
سأعترف بما أنّه لا جدوى من إخفاء الأمر الآن
but I've been secretly seeing Dr. Hatano!
!كنتُ في علاقة سرّية مع الطبيب هاتانو
What?!
!ماذا؟
But we're innocent!
!لكنّنا بريئان
We were both at the Beika Hotel from afternoon until evening!
!كنّا في فندق بيكا من الظهيرة للمساء
Are you sure the two of you didn't arrange to say the same story?!
ألم تتفقا على القصة نفسها وحسب؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Whatever the case, excluding old man Kogoro,
،أيّاً يكن، باستثناء العمّ كوغورو
none of the three visitors have alibis!
لا يملك أيّ من الزوّار الثلاثة حجّة غياب
Who did it?!
من كان القاتل؟
Hey! Not you again!
!أنت! تشاغب مجدداً
This is Hatano. Are you there, Maru-san?
أنا هاتانو، أأنت هنا يا مارو-سان؟
Oh, well. Anyway, I'll be there at 5:00, as we agreed.
حسناً، بأيّ حال سأصل عند الخامسة كالمتّفق
Call taken at 4:38.
جرى الاتّصال عند 4:38
This is Suwa.
أنا سوا
I was planning to be there at 6:00, but I think I may arrive early.
،كنتُ أخطط للوصول عند السادسة لكن قد أصل باكراً
I've made arrangements for next month's level examinations.
رتّبتُ لاختبارات مستوى الشهر القادم
I'll give you the details at a later time.
سأعطيك التفاصيل في وقت لاحق
Call taken at 4:41.
جرى الاتّصال عند 4:41
I see. Dr. Hatano was scheduled for 5:00.
فهمت، كان موعد الطبيب هاتانو عند الخامسة
Suwa-san was set for 6:00 but called ahead and arrived at 5:00, correct?
وموعد سوا-سان عند السادسة، لكنّك اتّصلت وقدّمت الموعد للخامسة، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
I left a message on the answering machine too!
!تركتُ رسالةً على آلة الردّ بدوري
Are you sure?
أأنت متأكد؟
I'm not lying!
!لا أكذب
I said I was going to be a little late but that I would pay him back!
قلتُ أنّي سأتأخر قليلاً لكني !سأعيد المال حتماً
I also told him that I would kill him if he sold it!
!أخبرتهُ أيضاً أنّي سأقتله إن باعه
You would kill him?!
ستقتله؟
Well, yeah, he threatened me.
أجل، فقد هدّدني
He said he would sell the carving I lent him if I didn't pay him back!
!أنّه سيبيع النحت الذي أعرته إيّاه إلم أردّ ماله
What kind of carving?
أيّ نحت؟
That dragon.
ذاك التنين
There's something strange about that carving!
هناك أمرٌ بذاك النحت
That's great! You weren't damaged one bit!
!حمداً لله! لم تصب بأيّ خدش
Good for you, mister! You're so lucky!
هذا رائع يا عمّ، حالفك الحظّ
It's a miracle that your carving was the only thing unharmed in this room!
نجاة ذاك النحت وحده من الخدوش معجزة
Aha, I've got it figured out now...
فهمت، توضّح الأمر لي الآن
Akutsu-san. You are the killer!
أكوتسو-سان، أنت القاتل
What?!
!ماذا؟
You killed Maru-san and tried to put the blame on Suwa-san.
قتلت مارو-سان وحاولت إلقاء اللوم على سوا-سان
But you made a couple mistakes.
لكنك اقترفت أخطاءً
First, you made the corpse hold the sword the wrong way.
الأوّل كان وضعك للسيف في قبضة الضحيّة مقلوباً
Second, you couldn't damage the dragon carving.
والثاني عجزك عن إضرار نحت التنين
It looks like you didn't mind killing someone,
،يبدو أنّك لم تمانع قتل نفس
but couldn't bear to bring harm to your precious carving!
لكنك لم تستطع أذيّة نحتك العزيز
This is just a coincidence!
!إنّها مصادفة فقط
Then why did you lie about leaving a message on his answering machine?!
لمَ كذبت بشأن ترك رسالة على آلة الردّ إذاً؟
I didn't lie! I really did leave a message!
!لم أكذب! تركتُ رسالةً حقاً
Come to think of it, the phone rang three times!
صحيح، رنّ الهاتف 3 مرّات
The 2nd and 3rd times, it stopped ringing right away,
في المرّة الثانية والثالثة، توقّف عن الرنين فوراً
but the first time...
...لكن في الأولى
...it kept ringing over and over!
رنّ مراراً...
Say, mister! Did anything seem strange when you called?
أخبرني يا عمّ، أكان هناك أمر غريب أثناء اتّصالك؟
Like maybe nobody would pick up, or something?
مثل عدم ردّ أحد؟
Now that you mention it, I left it ringing for a long time.
بذكرك لذلك، رنّ الهاتف لوقت طويل
Just when I thought I finally got through, I got his answering machine.
،وعندما ظننت أن اتّصالي سيُجاب أخيراً أجابتني آلة الردّ الآلي
Our answering machine is set to take messages after 10 rings.
آلة الردّ خاصتنا مضبوطة على تسجيل الرسائل بعد 10 رنّات
See? What did I tell you?
رأيت؟ أخبرتكم
What time did you call?
متى اتّصلت بالضبط؟
It was shortly before our appointment, so it was before 4:00.
قليلاً قبل موعدنا، لذا قبل الرابعة
You probably heard the phone ringing when you were killing Maru-san!
سمعتَ الهاتف يرنّ وأنت تقتل مارو-سان غالباً
So that's why you're giving us this nonsense!
لذا تتفوه بهذا الهراء
No! I really did leave a message!
!كلا! تركتُ رسالةً حقاً
How odd!
غريب
If he was the murderer,
،إن كان القاتل
then why would he concoct a lie that people would see through right away?
فلمَ سيختلق كذبةً سريعة الكشف كهذه؟
But there's no message from him on the answering machine...
لكن لا رسالة منه على آلة الردّ
Wait a second!
لحظة
Now that I think about it, there is someone who left a strange message!
!هناك من ترك رسالةً غريبة بالتدقيق في الأمر
One that nobody would normally leave...
...رسالة لا يتركها أحد في العادة
If so, then the killer is...
...مما يعني أنّ القاتل
Miss. Is there anything of value in here?
أهناك ما يحمل قيمةً في هذه الغرفة يا سيّدة؟
Yes, there's a safe key in one of the drawers!
أجل، يوجد مفتاح خزنة في أحد الأدراج
It's gone! The safe key is gone!
!اختفى! مفتاح الخزنة ليس موجوداً
What?!
!ماذا؟
So it was you!
!كان أنت بالفعل
Huh?
ماذا؟
Here it is. In a different drawer.
ها هو، إنّه في درج آخر
Miss...
...سـ-سيّدتي
But that's strange! My husband always kept it in this one!
لكن هذا غريب، يحتفظ به زوجي في هذا دوماً
These drawers!
!هذه الأدراج
None of the large sword cuts are connected!
!لا أحد من آثار السيف الكبيرة متّصل
Say, is there an instant camera in the house anywhere?
أتوجد كاميرا فورية في هذا المنزل؟
Yes...
...أجل
That inspector says he'd like to borrow it.
يقول المفتّش أنه يريد استعارتها
Okay, I'll go get it!
سأذهب لجلبها إذاً
What part of "get out of here" don't you understand?!
!أيّ جزء من "اغرب من هنا" لا تفهمه؟
Darn it!
!تباً
Oh well. At least I got my picture.
لا يهمّ، حصلت على الصورة على الأقل
Here it is!
!إنها تظهر
All I do now is...
...الباقي
...cut out the drawers with sword cuts that don't connect...
استخراج الأدراج بآثار السيف الكبيرة غير المرتبطة
Aha! So I was right!
!هكذا إذاً! كنتُ محقاً
I've solved this mystery!
!حللتُ اللغز
At any rate, I'll have to take you down to the station.
عليك مرافقتنا للمركز بأيّ حال
What?!
!ماذا؟
Come now, there's no use in denying it!
أنت، لا جدوى من إنكارك
Shut up! I didn't do it!
!اخرس! لم أكن الفاعل
What's he doing?
ما الذي يفعله؟
Well, let's go.
حسنٌ، هيّا بنا
Not so fast.
انتظروا لحظة
Mori-kun...
موري-كن
I've figured it out for sure this time, Inspector.
اكتشفتُ الأمر هذه المرّة سيّدي المفتش
Figured out who did it, that is.
اكتشفتُ هويّة المجرم
Who?!
!مـ-من هو؟
The murderer is...
...المجرم
...you, Suwa-san!
!هو أنت يا سوا-سان
Hey now, Suwa-san practices swordsmanship--
لكن سوا-سان يمارس المبارزة
he wouldn't have made the corpse hold the sword incorrectly...
فلا يمكن أنّه من أخطأ في وضع السيف في قبضة الضحيّة
That's why we were so easily fooled...
...هكذا خُدعنا بسهولة
...which is exactly what Suwa-san wanted!
وفق حساباته تماماً
What?
ماذا؟
To make himself look suspicious, he put sword cuts all over the room
لإثارة الشبهة حول نفسه، ملأ الغرفة بآثار السيف
and then put the sword in the victim's hands.
ثمّ وضع السيف في قبضة الضحيّة
But he provided himself with an escape route
لكنه فتح لنفسه مهرباً
by making the victim hold the sword incorrectly.
بجعل الضحيّة تمسك السيف بشكل غير صحيح
By doing this, he made it look like someone had tried to frame him,
وهكذا جعل الأمر كما لو أن أحدهم يحاول إلقاء التهمة عليه
and thus he was able to remove himself of any suspicion.
وأزال الشبهات عن نفسه تماماً
Mori-san.
موري-سان
Do you really intend to accuse me of this with nothing but conjecture?
أتنوي اتّهامي بهذا الاستنتاج الضعيف حقاً؟
He has a point, Mori-kun!
!معه حقّ يا موري-كن
And besides, how do you explain the dragon carving?!
وكيف تفسّر مسألة نحت التنين؟
You were the one who just accused Akutsu-san of being the murderer!
!كنتَ من اتّهم أكوتسو-سان بأنّه القاتل
I... was lying...
...كـ-كنتُ أكذب
Lying?!
!تكذب؟
Suwa-san purposely left it unharmed
تعمّد سوا-سان تركه سليماً
in order to make Akutsu-san look suspicious!
!لإثارة الشبهة حول أكوتسو-سان
Nonsense. This is the first time we've met.
مُحال، هذه أوّل مرة نلتقي فيها
How would I have known the dragon belonged to him?
كيف لي أن أعرف أنّ التنين يخصّه؟
The answering machine.
آلة الردّ الآلي
The phone call that Akutsu-san swore he made...
الاتصال الذي يصرّ أكوتسو-سان أنّه أجراه
My guess is that you heard it while committing the murder.
سمعتَه أثناء ارتكابك للجريمة غالباً
If you sell the dragon carving I left with you, I swear I'll kill you!
!إن بعت نحت التنين الذي تركته عندك سأقتلك
So you probably came up with a plan on the spot to frame Akutsu-san.
فخطرت لك فكرة إلفاق التهمة بأكوتسو-سان تلك اللحظة غالباً
But Akutsu-san's message wasn't on the tape!
!لكنّ رسالة أكوتسو-سان لم تكن مسجلة
That's because Suwa-san rewound the tape
هذا لأنّ سوا-سان أعاد الشريط للوراء
and recorded his own message over the first one!
وسجّل رسالته فوق الأولى
But Dr. Hatano could have done that too.
لكن كان يمكن للطبيب هاتانو فعل ذلك أيضاً
No...
كلّا
In your message, you confessed that you, yourself, were the murderer!
!اعترفت بأنّك القاتل في رسالتك
What?!
!ماذا؟
You left a message that you would arrive earlier than planned.
تركت رسالةً تفيد أنّك ستصل قبل الموعد المتّفق عليه
Don't you find that strange?
أليس ذلك غريباً؟
Going early to someone's house even though you know they're not home?
ذهابك لمنزل أحدهم باكراً رغم علمك أنّه ليس موجوداً؟
You said that because you knew that Maru-san was here, in the cottage,
قلت ذلك لأنّك كنت تعرف أنّ مارو-سان في الكوخ
as a corpse!
!كجثّة
Maru-san said he was meeting someone between 4:00 and 5:00,
قال مارو-سان أنّه سيلتقي شخصاً بين الرابعة والخامسة
so he asked me to come at any time other than that.
لذا طلب مني القدوم في أيّ وقت بخلاف ذلك
So I figured that coming before our appointed 6:00 was fine with him.
فظننتُ أن القدوم قبل السادسة المتّفق عليها أمراً مقبولاً
Do you still suspect me now?
لا تزال تشكّ بي؟
I don't suspect you of killing him.
لا أشكّ بقتلك له
I am certain of it!
!بل أنا متيقن... من أنك القاتل
What?!
!ماذا؟
There is definitive proof in this room that you are the murderer!
!يوجد دليل دامغ يدينك في هذه الغرفة
W-Where?!
!أ-أين؟
The real reason for cutting up the room was to conceal something!
سبب تقطيع الغرفة الحقيقي كان لإخفاء شيء
To conceal something?
إخفاء شيء؟
The marks on the drawers.
الآثار على الأدراج
Take a close look at the cut marks.
أمعنوا النظر في الآثار
Some of them aren't connected.
بعضها غير متصل
You're right!
!مـ-معك حق
The drawers were switched around purposely by the killer.
بدّل القاتل الأدراج عمداً
To put them back as they were,
لإعادتها لترتيبها الأصلي
take the drawer on the top row, 2nd from the left,
ابدأ بأخذ الدرج في الصف العلوي، الثاني من اليسار
and switch it with the rightmost drawer of the same row.
وبدّله مع الدرج في أقصى اليمين في الصف نفسه
Next, take the leftmost drawer of the next row down
ثمّ خذ الدرج في أقصى اليسار من الصفّ أسفله
and switch it with the leftmost drawer of the 5th row.
وبدّله مع الدرج أقصى اليسار في الصفّ الخامس
The 2nd row, 2nd column and the rightmost drawer of the same row.
درج العمود الثاني من الصف الثاني مع الدرج في أقصى اليمين للصفّ نفسه
3rd row, 2nd column and the rightmost drawer of the 4th row.
ودرج العمود الثاني في الصفّ الثالث مع الدرج أقصى اليمين في الصفّ الرابع
Finally, 5th row, 2nd column and the 4th row, 3rd column from the left.
وأخيراً، درج العمود الثاني في الصفّ الخامس مع درج العمود الثالث من اليسار في الصفّ الرابع
W-What is this?!
...هـ-هذا
"Suwa"?!
!سوا؟
My guess is that while Suwa-san was busy erasing Akutsu-san's message,
بينما كان سوا-سان مشغولاً بحذف رسالة أكوتسو-سان غالباً
the victim wrote this with his sword.
كتبها الضحيّة بسيفه
Having realized this, you switched the drawers around
بعد إدراكك لذلك، بدّلت الأدراج
and put your own cut marks on them to make the letters illegible.
وأضفت علاماتك الخاصة لتشويه الأحرف
But the drawers would stand out as the only things damaged,
لكن ستبرز الأدراج إن كانت وحدها المتضررة
so you cut up everything else in the room too.
فكان عليك تقطيع كلّ شيء في أرجاء الغرفة
All to conceal the victim's dying message to us,
كلّها لإخفاء رسالة احتضار الضحيّة لنا
which he had written on the drawers!
!التي كتبها على الأدراج
But why? You had the money to pay off your debt!
!لكن لمَ؟ كان يحمل المال لدفع الدَّين
Because of a sword.
بسبب سيف
A sword? The one the victim was holding?
سيف؟ الذي كان يحمله الضحيّة؟
No, not that dull excuse for a sword.
ليس ذاك السيف الكليل
The sword that I left with him as collateral...
...بل السيف الذي تركتهُ معه ضمان دَين
The family sword that has been passed down for generations...
...الذي توارثته عائلتي لأجيال
...the Kikuchiyo.
الكيكوتشيو
He had the nerve to...
...قام ذاك الرجل بـ
Oh, that sword? I sold it.
ذاك السيف؟ بعته بالفعل
It didn't go for very much, though.
لم يجن لي مالاً كثيراً
Let's consider the money I received for it as the interest on your loan.
حسناً، لنعتبر ذاك المال الذي استلمتُه فائدة على قرضك
Before I knew it, I had struck him down with the sword.
وفي غياب وعي، ضربتهُ بالسيف
Yes. Just like this!
!صحيح، هكذا
The rest happened just as you said.
والتالي جرى كما قلت
Even so, the fact that you didn't even flinch when I attacked...
...مع ذلك، عدم تزحزحك عندما هاجمت
You are indeed an extraordinary detective, Mori Kogoro-dono.
يظهر أنك مُتحرٍّ عظيم حقاً يا موري كوغورو-دونو
It would seem that my greatest mistake
يبدو أنّ أكبر أخطائي
was not realizing that you were here.
كان عدم إدراكي لكونك هنا
That was amazing, Dad!
!كان ذلك مذهلاً يا أبي
I've changed my opinion of you again!
!غيرت نظرتي عنك مجدداً
Oh? There's something on your head...
ماذا؟ هناك شيءٌ على رأسك
Blood! It's blood! I'm bleeding!
!دم! إنّه دم! أنا أنزف
Make me some food already!
!جهّزي طعامي فقط
Could you get Inspector Megure?
أيمكنكم إيصالي بالمفتش ميغوري؟
A thief gang in the department store?
عصابة لصوص في مركز التسوق؟
The Department Store Hijack.
سرقة مركز التسوق
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Elevator girl.
مضيفة مصعد